That night, murder wasn't the only sin.
Agnes of God is a drama, mystery film directed by Norman Jewison.
When a dead newborn is found, wrapped in bloody sheets, in the bedroom wastebasket of a young novice, psychiatrist Martha Livingston is called in to
determine if the seemingly innocent novice, who knows nothing of sex or birth, is competent enough to stand trial for the murder of the baby.
Dr. Martha Louise Livingston, played by Jane Fonda.
Sister Agnes, played by Meg Tilly.
Mother Miriam Ruth, played by Anne Bancroft.
Dr. Livingston's Mother, played by Anne Pitoniak.
Det. Larry Langevin, played by Winston Rekert.
Father Martineau, played by Gratien Gélinas.
Agnes of God is a 1985 American mystery film directed by Norman Jewison
and starring Jane Fonda, Anne Bancroft and Meg Tilly.
It was written by John Pielmeier, based on his 1979 play of the same name.
The plot is about a novice nun (Tilly) who gives birth and insists that
the dead child was the result of a virginal conception.
A psychiatrist (Fonda) and the mother superior (Bancroft) of the
convent clash during the resulting investigation.
Despite generally mixed reviews from critics, the film was nominated for three Academy Awards:
Best Actress (Bancroft), Best Supporting Actress (Tilly), and Best Original Score.
Tilly won the Golden Globe for Best Supporting Actress, while Bancroft was nominated
for the Golden Globe Award for Best Actress in a Motion Picture – Drama.
Pielmeier received a Writers Guild of America
Award nomination for his screenplay.
The film was a financial success, as it grossed $25,627,836
domestically against a $7.5 million budget.
The film explores themes of court, nun, quebec, hypnosis, montreal, canada.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.